Guide to the Matthew Charles Rosenblum Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Matthew Charles Rosenblum papers
2000-2006
MS 1883
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The digital images consist of Cherry Grove celebrities and royalty at various functions, including teas, beauty contests, and the annual Invasion of the Pines. The images are crafted using the digital equivalents of photography, stage makeup, and cosmetic surgery.
Rosenblum, Matthew Charles
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Matthew Charles Rosenblum, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Chronologically by year and alphabetically by title within each year.
Biographical / Historical
Matthew Charles Rosenblum was born on June 7, 1947, in New Jersey. His interest in photography began when he was eight years old, and by age 16 he amassed an extensive collection of United States national parks images. He graduated from the University of Arizona in 1970, and then earned an advanced degree in psychology from the New School for Social Research. Between 1974 and 1977, he took month-long photographic explorations in the Andes and Amazonas and Southeast Asia. In 1978, he met John Piazza, and for the next twenty-two years they traveled extensively in the Americas, Europe, Africa, and Asia where Rosenblum captured expressions of culture and lifestyle in his portraits of the locals. Beginning in 2000, they became seasonal residents of Cherry Grove on Fire Island, New York, where they started to go by the name of The Hoffas. The name originated from Rosenblum's adoption of Gimmi Hoffa as his nom-de-caméra and the local lore that Jimmy Hoffa, the Teamster leader, was in a federal witness protection program and living in Cherry Grove. Rosenblum's photographs are exhibited in homes and business establishments in Cherry Grove. In 2005 he joined the Board of the Arts Project of Cherry Grove.
Scope and Contents
The digital images consist of Cherry Grove celebrities and royalty at various functions, including teas, beauty contests, and the annual Invasion of the Pines. The images are crafted using the digital equivalents of photography, stage makeup, and cosmetic surgery.
Female impersonators; Cherry Grove (N.Y.); Color photographs; LGBTQ resource; Rosenblum, Matthew Charles
- Inventory
  - 2000, Philomena, Cherry Grove Ball (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 2001
    - Fluffy, Fluffy's Tea (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Widow Norton & Billie Ann Miller, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2002
    - Ariel Sinclair, Miss Fire Island Contest (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bella, Miss Fire Island Contest (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2003
    - Anita Greenkard, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Gefil Tefish, Miss Fire Island Contest (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Josie, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Robyn Kradles, Miss Fire Island Contest (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - The Shapiros, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Vanessa Vale, Miss Fire Island Contest (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 2004
    - Charity, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - China, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Good & Plenty, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Hooters, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Luisa Verde, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Rose, P.A.W.S. Benefit (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Urban Sprawl, Casino (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Wynn & Peter, 57th Anniversary (Partners) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 2005
    - Anne Tique, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Boon, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Peter B., Invasion (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Mandi, Dr.'s House Fundraiser Show (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Sybil Bruncheon, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Violet Silver, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 2006
    - Bill & Antoinette, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Cobra, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Coco Love & Lola, Dr.'s House Fundraiser (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Dakota Sue, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Don, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Donna Pirhana, Leather Tea (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Ginger More, Dr.'s House Fundraiser (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - The Go Go Girls, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Jacqueline Jonée, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Ivanna Cocktail, Dr.'s House Fundraiser (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Orangina, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Panzi, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Samantha X (as Mother Nature), Invasion (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Viva Sex & Nikki Star, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Wyonna, Invasion (Box 1, Folder 40)